#### Contact

Mobile: 01755025013

Address: House-324, Lane-5, Baridhara, DOHS, -Cant. 1206, Dhaka Cantonment

Email: titly007@yahoo.com

Social Media:

www.linkedin.com/in/tabassum-binte-islam-64503733 (LinkedIn)

# Top Skills:

## Human Resource Skills:

Recruitment
Screening
Performance Management Training
Conduct
Policy and Procedure

Personal Skills: Leadership Communication Problem Solving

# Languages

Bengali (Native or Bilingual) English (Full Professional)

### Certifications

Course on "Bangladesh Labor Law"
Training on "Managing People
Effectively"

# **Tabassum Binte Islam**

Manager, HR at Bangladesh Legal Aid and Services Trust (BLAST) Bangladesh

# Career Objective

Self-motivated professional with 10 years of Human Resources experience well versed in designing and administrating recruiting, on-boarding and performance management plans looking to continue to develop as a well rounded human resource specialist

# Summary

My total work experience is 13 years' including 10 years' in Human resource in both field and head office based. My Core expertise is on Talent Acquisition (Recruitment-Selection-Placement) and Organizational Development. Also have experienced in HR Policy Formulation, Assessment center, training, Induction Program, Performance Management System (PMS), Employer branding, activities on social media, career fair etc. I also had experience in customer service and Corporate Corresponding (National & International).

I have done my Masters in English from East West University and also have Post graduate Diploma in HRM. Also I am doing Masters in Development Studies from BRAC University.

#### Achievement & Reward:

- (i) Policy Formulation: Developed & formulated BRAC's latest HR policy as a key person;
- (ii) PMS workshop: conducted PMS workshop for all supervisor as per new e-PMS policy;
- (iii) Talent Acquisition: Have conducted bulk recruitment & selection for field force, also conducted MTO recruitment & head-hunting project and assist to run assessment center
- (iv) Employer Branding & Job Fair: Developed & organized job advertisement, career fair at different university, campaigning through social media;
- (v) Induction Training: Conducted & developed induction program for management level staff at corporate office;

(vi) Scholarship: On the basis of my performance BRAC rewarded me full-scholarship "Masters on Development Management" at BRAC University;

# Experience

Bangladesh Legal Aid and Services Trust (BLAST)
Manager, HR
August 2021 - Present (10 months)

- >Develop and implement HR strategies and initiatives aligned with the overall business strategy
- >Bridge management and employee relations by addressing demands, grievances or other issues
- >Manage the recruitment and selection process
- >Managing company staff, including coordinating
- >Onboarding newcomers to the company
- >Determining suitable salaries and remuneration
- >Providing the necessary support systems for payroll requirements
- >Support current and future business needs through the development, engagement, motivation and preservation of human capital
- >Develop and monitor overall HR strategies, systems, tactics and procedures across the organization

Nurture a positive working environment

- >Oversee and manage a performance appraisal system that drives high performance
- >Assess training needs to apply and monitor training programs
- >Report to management and provide decision support through HR metrics
- >Ensure legal compliance throughout human resource management
- >Supporting employee opportunities for professional development
- >Managing succession planning of staff

### **BRAC**

9 years

Deputy Manager, Recruitment April 2018 - August 2021 (3 years 5 months)

#### Recruitment:

>Managing whole Recruiting process - this includes developing job descriptions and person specifications, preparing job adverts, checking application forms, shortlisting, interviewing and selecting candidates

- >Draft job descriptions, vacancy announcements, compiling matrixes, performing functions of Secretary in interview panels
- >Negotiating with staff and their representatives (for example, trade union officials) on issues relating to pay and conditions
- >Assist for talent acquisition and head-hunting process
- >Assist to run Assessment center
- >Promoting equality and diversity as part of the culture of the organisation

Officer, HR (Talent Sourcing & OD)
January 2014 - March 2018 (4 years 3 months)

BRAC Head Office, Dhaka, Bangladesh

- -To coordinate, manage & conduct recruitment-placement-selection process;
- -To manage & assist for talent acquisition and head-hunting process;
- -To manage & organize the departmental retreat, events & cultural fictions;
- -To develop & conduct Policy Orientation, Induction Training and PMS workshop;
- -To make & submit draft HR policy bench-marking with ILO, Bangladesh Labor & Industrial Law, GO-NGO and other related pressure group's amendment & section;
- -To communicate and coordinate top & 2nd tire management for FGD/Meeting/ Workshop regarding HR policy formulation and approval;
- -To communicate, coordinate and manage focal person of other department to circulate the new policy, procedure or any new HR amendment;
- -To conduct and coordinate compliance monitoring regarding any issue of HR policy;
- -To make draft of circular/office order/office memo, manage cross check through proper management and circulate it within the organization;

#### **HR Officer**

September 2012 - December 2013 (1 year 4 months)

Divisional HR Office, Rangpur, Bangladesh

- -To coordinate & manage staff recruitment-selection-placement process;
- -To conduct induction training, policy orientation, PMS workshop;
- -To ensure HR services (payroll, salary, bonus, increment, adjustment, promotion, etc);
- -To ensure, manage, entry & update HR software and data-management (HRMS, EDMS);
- -Identify HR related issues and ensure timely delivery of staff benefit relate documents:
- -Disseminate HR policy, procedure and ensure its compliance;

- Frequent field visits to strengthen cohesiveness with employee;
- Prepare and disburse Appointment & Confirmation Letter, Transfer Order, ID card etc. as and when required.
- Effective interaction with different programs/projects of BRAC to achieve a clear understanding on their activities,
- Ensure the performance appraisal (PMS) timely and in qualitative way;
- Assist line manager to identify required development areas for his/her line employees;
- Participate in different meetings and forums with the field level staff;
- To communicate, coordinate and collaborate with local, national and international GO/NGO regarding different social issues.
- To manage & coordinate official events, occasions, HR retreat, BRAC day, National day, etc.

#### Enam Labels Ltd.

Executive, Customer Service October 2010 - August 2012 (1 year 11 months)

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Intelligent Image Management Ltd Supervisor (Team Leader) August 2008 - September 2010 (2 years 2 months) Dhaka, Bangladesh

# Education

# **BRAC University**

Master's Degree, Development Studies · (2015 - 2018)

# East West University

Master in English, Language, Literature & General · (2008 - 2010)

### National University of Bangladesh

Bachelor in English, Language, Literature & General · (2003 - 2008)

#### References

Azmiree Sultana Senior Manager, Finance & Accounts Manger **BRAC** 

email: azmeeree05@gmail.com Phone: 8801730374232

Ariful Haider PRAN-RFL

email: arif\_grades@yahoo.com

Phone: 8801617055646